Hello there! I want to make sure you have a good time and that you don't get stuck
on anything relating to connecting to our lab environment. Some of the material
you're going to be learning is tricky enough, so you'll have enough on your
mind with just that. Let's make sure that logging into our system and
navigating around is as smooth and painless as possible. You'll be logging
into an actual IBM Z system, and this is separate from whatever learning
platform you're on. To get you connected will also be giving you access to a
virtual Windows system, and that has all of the connection software preloaded on
it, and you'll use that to connect to the mainframe system. This is the easiest way
to get you connected without having you to install all sorts of software on your
own machine. When you go to connect to the lab system, you'll eventually see a
loading screen that looks something like this, and then something like this, and
then something like this, and then eventually you'll get to a screen that
looks something like this, with the green box and the course lab kit up here.
This is your connection to that system, and there's three important things on
here that I want to show you. First is the lab kit up top here. That link
wasn't there until the system was ready. This is a document made just for you, and
it has your connection information in it. You'll need that information, so maybe
bookmark it or print it out so you can find it easily later on. This page also
shows you the amount of time left. Now, this is not the amount of time left in
the course. Remember, two separate things. This is the amount of time left on the
hands-on system, and if you need more time to get your work done on the system,
go down to support. There's a link in your course lab kit, and then visit the
self-service portal to request an extension, and just so you know, the time
to do that is before you need that extra time, and the sooner the better.
Trust me on this, you don't want to wait until the last minute, or they
might not be able to change it in time, and you might lose all of your work
on that system. So pay attention to that date. Alright, you got that. Last thing is
your virtual system access. This is that virtual Windows system that I talked
about earlier, and you'll use this to connect to the IBM Z mainframe system.
This will normally say running, but if you ever come in here after a while and
it says busy, then you probably just have to wait a little while for it to come
back online. No big deal. This is also a good time to point out that
sometimes you'll see values on your screen that are just examples. Things
like user IDs and high-level qualifiers. Now eventually you'll be able to spot
those right away, no problem, but when you see something that maybe looks like
your user ID but isn't actually your user ID, you're probably expected to put
in your user ID, not the one you see on the screen. You wouldn't believe how
often someone copies and pastes a command exactly as it is into the system,
and then they get really frustrated when it doesn't work. So double-check the
examples, double-check the instructions, and make sure you're entering what
you're supposed to enter. To get into this system, you'll need a username and
password, and I can't tell it to you and we can't make it log in automatically.
The username and password are in your course lab kit. Remember that link up
at the top of the screen? Now there are two usernames and passwords in here. The
first one is for getting into that Windows system. It's in the remote
access information section. Then below that, in lab information, you'll find these
student TSO user IDs, and it might just be one, it might be two, it'll probably
just be one, but you'll use those credentials to log into the mainframe
system, which we'll cover in the next video. I hope that helps you get off to a
great start with the labs in your course. Have fun and learn a lot.